Luis Miguel Palacio Restrepo

luis@palaciorestrepo.com



+34 618380017



linkedin.com/in/Impalacio



http://www.palaciorestrepo.com/lm

Summary

I'm passionate about technologies that evoke emotions and create momentous. Which has driven my career towards AR/VR development specializing in XR Interactions and Immersive Experiences.

I have been in the industry since 2016, and I dream in a world where anyone could reach their full potential with immersive technologies.

Moreover, with a background in entertainment and cognitive systems, I am very interested in Social Computing and the cultural implications of Artificial Intelligence.

Experience



Chief Technology Officer

DTOWN

Aug 2020 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

- Exploration of cutting-edge technology related to Extended Reality by using Fast-prototyping techniques to develop experimental applications for Hololens, NReal AR Glasses, Mobile-based AR, and Virtual Reality devices; including interactive 360 videos, Motion Capture, LiDar scans, and Photogrammetry.
- Participant and speaker in VRDays 2021 Europe.
- PR/Merged +4000 commits to develop working MVP with Multiplayer System, Virtual spaces, Interactive elements, and In-game creation tools.
- Whitepaper definition based on deep market research focused on the Metaverse Industry.
- Lead Developer of a small team intended to build a whitelabel Metaverse compatible with AR, VR, and Desktop devices.
- Definition of main features, architecture, and Customer Journey Map for an experimental virtual world inspired by the 90's Sci-fi movies.



Innovation Developer

TODO1 Services

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 1 month)

- Conceptualize and Design prototypes; test and deploy key features including API networking, NLP for virtual assistants/chatbots, and development of mobile applications.
- Formulate and implement new design decisions and product directions based on user testing observations.
- Leverage user testing observations to create and implement innovative product directions and design decisions.
- Employ critical thinking and complex problem-solving skills to identify potential areas for improvement and create actionable solutions.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams toward the timely achievement of project and organizational objectives under Scrum-based methodologies.

Apprentice of Innovation

TODO1 Services

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018 (7 months)

- Design and development of applications focused on the financial sector.
- Implementation and deployment of virtual assistants/chatbots on Facebook Messenger and Skype For Business.
- Development of mobile applications in Android, iOS, and Web Mobile; using OutSystems and Unity C#.
- Participation in projects from their early stages of conceptualization until its MVP is reached.

System Software Developer

PikPok S.A.S (Antes Wizard Fun Factory)

Sep 2017 - Sep 2017 (1 month)

• Definition and implementation of low-level protocols to communicate interactive installations, including lights control, sensors, and Unity applications.

Education

upf Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Master in Cognitive Systems and Interactive Media, Human Computer Interaction Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

- Conducted multiple experiments aimed at the analysis of declarative and behavioral data to define new interaction paradigms within a projective AR experience in the Museu d'Història de Barcelona (MUHBA).
- Designed and developed Unity applications for user testing and research in Cognitive Science and HCI.

Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana

Digital Entertainment Engineering, Engineering

2014 - 2018

- Focus on interactive experiences, concept definition, and fast prototyping.
- Worked closely with Costa Rica's Museum of Children to design and prototype interactive installations.

Licenses & Certifications

Máster en Programación de Videojuegos con Unity® 2020 y C# - Udemy UC-f124eb9e-e5a2-4435-aee1-2075e3959580

HX CS50's Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with Python - HarvardX

d40b027da0fb41b5a40c50e7e753322e

Skills

Virtual Reality (VR) • Augmented Reality (AR) • Unity • Interaction Design • C# • Metaverse • User Interface Prototyping • Software Development • Video Games • Node.js